<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scovl</title>
    <link>https://scovl.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on scovl</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>pt</language>
    <copyright>Vitor Lobo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 19:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://scovl.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning anything</title>
      <link>https://scovl.github.io/2023/09/09/learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 18:00:45 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://scovl.github.io/2023/09/09/learn/</guid>
      <description>Tips and tricks to learn everything There are numerous techniques for learning anything. There is even a course called Learning How to Learn on the Coursera platform. The one that works for me and that I recommend is the Pomodoro technique. The Pomodoro technique involves dividing time into 25-minute blocks, separated by short 5-minute breaks.&#xA;After 4 blocks of 25 minutes, you take a longer 15-minute break. The name Pomodoro comes from the fact that the creator of the technique used a tomato-shaped timer (Pomodoro in Italian).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus</title>
      <link>https://scovl.github.io/2023/03/21/prometheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 23:18:18 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://scovl.github.io/2023/03/21/prometheus/</guid>
      <description>Introdução Instalação Promtool Instrumentação Alertmanager PushGateway Federação Under the Hood Introdução Prometheus O Prometheus é uma ferramenta de monitoramento de sistemas e aplicativos open source. Foi desenvolvida com o objetivo de fornecer uma forma eficiente de coletar, armazenar e analisar métricas de desempenho de sistemas distribuídos. Ele foi projetado para ser escalável, fácil de usar e altamente personalizável. Possui sua própria linguagem de consulta, chamada PromQL, que permite aos usuários criar consultas complexas para analisar os dados de métricas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PromQL</title>
      <link>https://scovl.github.io/2023/03/19/promql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 17:31:45 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://scovl.github.io/2023/03/19/promql/</guid>
      <description>Introdução Funções Agregadores e Operadores PromQL na prática Erros comuns Introdução PromQL é uma linguagem de consulta poderosa usada para realizar consultas e configurar alertas sobre dados coletados pelo Prometheus. Seu principal objetivo é possibilitar a análise e monitoramento de métricas, como requisições HTTP por segundo ou a média de utilização de CPU por servidor, por meio de expressões que definem cálculos específicos. Importante para os usuários do Prometheus, a PromQL suporta funções matemáticas, operações booleanas e de comparação, agrupamento de dados e agregações.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java e Clojure</title>
      <link>https://scovl.github.io/2024/07/18/oop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://scovl.github.io/2024/07/18/oop/</guid>
      <description>Ao estudar diferentes linguagens de programação ao longo dos anos, fui atraído pela família Lisp devido à sua simplicidade e poder. Lisp, criado por John McCarthy em 1958, é conhecido por suas características distintas, como a notação de código como listas de dados (daí o nome LISt Processing) e sua capacidade de manipular código como uma estrutura de dados. Emacs Lisp e Common Lisp são dois dos muitos dialetos que evoluíram a partir do Lisp original, cada um com suas próprias peculiaridades e casos de uso.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://scovl.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://scovl.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Vitor. 👋 Hello, my name is Vitor Lobo, also known as (scovl) in the community. &amp;ldquo;Scovl&amp;rdquo; is a play on words combining &amp;lsquo;Scoville&amp;rsquo; and my name—Sco from Scott and Vitor Lobo, making Scovl. It refers to the Scoville scale, which measures the heat level of peppers, and I have a particular passion for peppers, especially the nuclear-hot ones. I&amp;rsquo;m a Software Engineer, a writer, a gamer and an independent researcher.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://scovl.github.io/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://scovl.github.io/page/contact/</guid>
      <description> E-mail: lobocode@gmail.com Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/vitor-lobo/ Mastodon: https://hachyderm.io/@lobocode </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://scovl.github.io/page/about.en/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://scovl.github.io/page/about.en/</guid>
      <description>Hello, welcome to my blog. I&amp;rsquo;m a Software Engineer, writer, gamer and independent researcher. I have been working professionally with technology for about 10 years. Outside of work I like literature, art, cinema, music, comics, manga, anime, a good beach, riding a bike and enjoying my free time with my partner and taking care of our cats. I am also involved in free/open source software initiatives such as Taverna dos Javeiros,Marmota Project, Project Atomic, Fedora Project.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
